Maarten Derks



Amsterdam, Netherlands +31 6 133 699 05

mail@maartenderks.nl in LinkedIn GitHub

SUMMARY

Broadly educated software engineer with experience in the banking and electronics industries. In my roles at Fairphone I provided an Android phone with software support for over 7 years, which is unprecedented. I am passionate about expanding my own learning and professional development, and I am at my best when working collaboratively with others. In my off-time I enjoy reading, working out and learning to play the guitar.

EXPERIENCE

FAIRPHONE 2015 - Present

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

2021 - Present

- Plan and execute the software support roadmap for one of Fairphone's products until its end of life
- Contribute to software engineering activities for other Fairphone products
- Improve and expand test infrastructure, look into test automation

2019 - 2021

- Take over responsibility of software engineering activities for one of Fairphone's products
- · Following an internal reorganization, find and onboard an external software engineering partner
- Conduct a feasibility study for developing another Android upgrade without SoC vendor support
- Lead both internal and external resources in the development of an Android upgrade

ANDROID PLATFORM ENGINEER

INTERN - PRODUCT TEAM

2016 - 2019

Feature porting, Android upgrade development, app development, security maintenance

JUNIOR ANDROID SOFTWARE ENGINEER

2015 - 2016

· OTA update deployment, GMS test suites, app development, open sourcing, security maintenance

2015

Master thesis: Fair Privacy: Improving Usability of the Android Permission System

SNS REAAL 2011 - 2012

INTERN

• Graduation project: Port online banking desktop website features to the mobile website

EDUCATION _

RADBOUD UNIVERSITY 2012 - 2015

MSc in Computer Science

- Specialisation: Software Construction, Quality of Software
- Subsidiary subject: Security/Privacy

AVANS UNIVERSITY OF APPLIED SCIENCES

2008 - 2012

BACHELOR OF INFORMATION AND COMMUNICATION TECHNOLOGY

• Minors: Software Architecture, Game Development

SKILLS

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES Experienced: Java | Python | Bash Familiar: C | C++ | Kotlin | Rust | C# | Haskell

MARKUP LANGUAGES HTML | CSS | XML | JSON | YAML | TeX | Markdown Git | Jenkins | Gerrit | GitLab | DevOps | Test automation SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT

AOSP | Qualcomm BSPs | Linux kernel | GMS | Security | OTA | Tradefed ANDROID PROGRAMMING

> Native: Dutch Full Professional: English Elementary: German | French LANGUAGES

June 4, 2024 / source code

TECH LEAD - SOFTWARE LONGEVITY TEAM